Eduardo Guerrero

Langton Lodge, N16 8SU, London United Kingdom



eduardo.guerrero.contact@gmail.com

I am a versatile product design consultant with more than 9 years of experience in the innovation sector, helping companies (from start-ups to multinational corporations) launch strategic products, services and ideas to the market using design thinking methodologies.

Work Experience

Senior Product Design Consultant - Full Time

Company: ROKi Digital 04/2021- Current (London)

Principal Product Designer for a variety of projects across different sectors (Fintech, Ecommerce, SaaS...):

- Defining UX processes and methodologies within the company
- · Defining the workflow between the company and the different stakeholders using Figma
- · Delivering research workshops (Persona, Empathy Maps, New Business Canvas, SWOT, Prioritisation...)
- Creating Low/Mid fidelity prototypes to test in front of users (includes A/B testing, remote testing, interviews post website use...).
- · Designing and building clients' Design Systems.
- · Defining the UI and brand identity.

Senior Product Design Consultant - Contractor

Company: webegin.today 05/2020- 02/2021 (London)

Principal Product Designer for the start-up "webegin.today", a job platform that prevents bias from the hiring company by the creation of an anonymous process when applying for a job:

- Designing the website flow, building wireframes and information architecture to define the website experience and the new hiring process.
- Defining the UI and brand identity of the website and company.
- One to one user interviews (hiring managers and website users) to learn about the problems they encounter when hiring or job hunting, and converting them to insights to solve in the new platform.
- Creation of Low/Mid fidelity prototypes to test in front of users to get their insights and iterate on the website interface and experience (includes A/B testing, remote testing, interviews post website use...).

Senior Product Design Consultant - Contractor

Company: Doble 11/2019 - 04/2020 (London)

Working to improve the UX of the products and giving support to the team with design related topics:

- · Low/Mid Prototyping of manuals (digital and print) using Agile methodology
- · Creating the new UI for the manuals and on-line content
- · Defining the style of the new products catalogue

Mid-Weight Product Design Consultant

Company: Studio Make Believe 06/2016 - 06/2019 (London)

Working on the UX, design, visual execution and engineering of ideas from different sectors (Transport, Medical, POS, Marketing,..):

- User and Environment Research to gain insights and inputs to detect problems or new opportunities for the brief. This includes final user interviews, stakeholders interviews, client data analysis, customer journey...
- · Ideation of new concepts answering client briefs (hand sketching, Solidworks, Rhino,...)
- · Generation of visuals to show ideas, finishes and materials (Sketching and Rendering)
- Engineering of new products from a prototype (3D printing, CNC, laser cutting, metal bending...) to mass production
- · Supplier engagement and management
- · Creating and delivering client presentations

Jr Product Design Consultant - Freelance

Company: Freelance 06/2015 - 06/2016 (Barcelona)

Implementation of projects related to design for SMEs across different sectors:

- · Client and stakeholder management
- · Cash-flow, budget control, invoicing...
- Full project delivery, from concept to manufacture

Jr Product Design Consultant

Company: Loop New Business Models 03/2013 - 06/2015 (Barcelona)

Project management in the field of product design, from product conceptualisation, external team coordination, structuring of content, creating and delivering client presentations:

- · Control of cash-flow, supplier orders...
- Multitask simultaneous projects at different stages and different scopes: FMCG, Home Appliances, Industrial equipment, Health, Packaging, Merchandise...
- Design thinking application; Brainstorm and sketchstorm organisation, storyboard application, map of actors ...)

Education

Front-end Engineer

Codecademy Certificate 02/2021 - 08/2021 (London)

Data Analysis for Management

London School of Economics Certificate 12/2018 - 03/2019 (London)

Industrial Design Engineering

ELISAVA Degree 09/2009 - 07/2013 (Barcelona)

Graphic Design Technician

Cipsa Diploma 06/2012 - 12/2012 (Barcelona)

Technical Architecture

UPC Degree 09/2006 - 06/2009 (Barcelona)

Awards

Red Dot Design Award 2016

Part of the design team in the CWP V3 / Evolution Air Traffic controller working position for Indra.

Technical Skills

- Advanced Figma (including Atomic Design and Design Systems)
- · Advanced Sketch
- · Advanced Adobe Pack (Adobe XD, Illustrator, Photoshop, Adobe Indesign)
- · Intermediate CSS/HTML
- · Basic Javascript
- Tableau (Data analysis)
- · Advanced Microsof Office (Word, Powerpoint, Excel)
- Design thinking tools and methodologies (Brainstorming, UCD, Personas, Service Blueprints, Stakeholders maps, User interviews...)

Languages

- English (Fluent)
- · Spanish (Native)
- · Catalan (Native)